Hi po Good day my name is Dennis bolon
from Sun Life insurance of Canada for
today I will help you to understand how
online application works when
we apply or have an interest
to apply for Sun Life insurance
But we are far from the main office So
basically Uh once again My name is
Dennis Buan I've been in the
insurance industry for more than si
years so I have Uh more or less thousand
of clients now Um in the Philippines and
also other countries po mga ofws po So
basically I will just share
my screen  to
you so My name is Dennis
bulaon I've been in the industry for
almost 6 years so Before joining Sun
Life I've been with Uh I was with hsbc
life insurance in Singapore so I help
hundreds of clients in Singapore and
then I also join Sun Life insurance of
Canada so ah I have clients
in the Philippines who are Actually applying
for Sun Life so Uh for today there are
Actually two important things that we
need to understand Uh first one we have
to identify or determine What exactly
your needs and second  That's the budget
so the  first one is Actually the needs
so there are comprises or compositions
of life insurance the first one is
the life insurance itself which is in
colloquial term or layman's term this is
what is called the benefit or
the final benefit that is obtained or
received by the beneficiaries not in
the event that the client or the
policy holder loses the other one is the
educational plan Third is the retirement
plan
investment and savings policy hospital
plan and medical plan there are Riders
that we put in life insurance
in the major plan Uh that actually fits the
preference or needs of the client and
then secondly your budget
Regarding the budget
Um there's Actually like a financial
management Uh rule or rule of thumb 50
30 20 rule or this is what they call
budgeting rule 50% of your gross income
let's say every 15th or 30 of the
month your salary is your gross
income 50% of your gross gross
income you need to set aside for your
needs then for the  30% once then 20%
is for the savings so this is where Papas
comes in for ah life insurance or the one for
investment So if you need life
insurance you need an educational
plan for your kids for retirement plan
for hospitalization plan and for other
things for investment plan so we have to
allocate 20% of your gross income um to
the savings or suit to the life
insurance so It's easy to
apply there are only some Uh
requirements so Sun Life is very simple
very
standard when  requirements so we
just only require clients to provide Uh
their valid ID government ID he must have a
signature SSS number or tin
Actually It's SSS or tin ah either or
then photo and selfie with ID seems to
be there in what in the picture po the
general information sheet and then
initial payment of premium so for the
initial payment of premium you can
choose um quarterly semi-annual or half
yearly or annual or yearly Okay so this is the
general information that Uh
We always ask Uh from the clients so
we have a template for this that is sent
We put it on messenger because we
don't want our clients to  Uh fill out
the form by them because it's hard to
edit so we do
it or our secretary does it So these are the
standard questionnaires
or information that we are asking
from the clients to provide so even
on messenger they can edit it
then Once they are complete or once this
information is complete they can
just Uh send us back Uh through
messenger so we
encode
it so after we get the
information so so This is the sample
application form we got It's a 10 page
Uh document so we encode
all the information then It includes the
proposal The valid ID as
well as the
Uh payment Uh transaction or receipt of the
client so this is an example proposal Uh
It's a it consists of 19 pages So this is
just the first page I will show
you because it's also Uh
restricted and ah it still needs to be private private private
private
So this is just a
sample plan just to give you an idea so
This is the five in one plan Uh  25
years old male nons smoke moker so Ah
this is the minimum Uh face amount
which is 350,000 but it has a multiplier
of Uh times 2 so it will be 700,000 the Deb
benefit or the final Uh final benefit
for the for the for the benefit
fisheries so he also has Riders
additional benefits so these are
Actually optional Uh we call it Riders
or the addons so he also has total
disability benefit waver of premium
Accidental death benefit critical
illness benefit hospital income benefit
so in the Uh next pages
they have comprehensive explanations
how the Riders work so I won't
show him first ah because we also have
the ah information we keep
especially the ah fund value or the
projected benefit that will be available for this
certain age so This information is the
general information we will encode
in the application form to Uh
together with the proposal form Uh the
id the payment and other documents so
we will do ah we will do
ah
link for the client so This is what
we will do So Once it is encoded
We have the
information so after the client sends the
link to his email or when
we have the link the client will do
so for example the cellphone
number so we will send a six digit
authentication code via SMS to your
mobile number to proceed so the client will
send a code so the client will receive
that code Like for example this one and
then
ah he will be able to see all of the
documents so check first
he will click on the view
application form view proposal view
client suitability assessment then view
client confirmation
then ah  click add
signature so please add signature and
your location then place your signature
just draw it using your mobile phone or
your tablet or your iPad then
click apply to reflect your signature on
the
forms then once you click save Uh So um
make sure all information is
correct before you save para po ma avoid let's
avoid ER and then after
signing the forms click continue then
upload the required documents So you
don't have to upload anything because
we have uploaded the other
information Then after  hitting submit
wait for the confirmation email  po and
then you will be able to receive a
Congratulations message in
your email so this is the
hard copy document you will receive after 1 to
two weeks and then this is the one inside
the contract and then you are also
able to pay Uh using Uh video online or
at the branch because we will provide one
time serial number or Iyung application
serial number then another one is ppi
either at the branch or at online You can
also pay using your GCash Uh account so
just look for bills then ah
insurance then Sun Life of Canada
Philippines  incorporated That's the
second one We'll choose the
second one then um just input or enter
the required amount to pay either
quarterly semi-annually or annually you
can do it Uh through GCash Then just
enter policy number ups number your
policy holders name your complete name
po including your middle name then your
email address So you are able to receive
Uh an email confirmation You can also go
to the branch or to Uh paying on banking
from Metrobank Security Bank and then
once The application is approved po
after 1 to two days Uh  just download on
your iOS on your iPhone or on  Android
device po ninyo itong Sun mobile
app then create account using your email
address that you used during application
create your own password then you are
able to see and monitor your insurance
po Okay so
This is the other information that
you can consider such
as the other plans that you can
apply so Normally the very famous ones that
clients apply for Ayung
pong 5 in one It's a little
loading
so these are the plans that you can
apply aside from certain PLs that
clients apply for just to give you
an idea po
okay Stop sharing me first stop sharing just
to make sure you can see it
Okay
aan so This is Actually very famous very
popular that people apply for
like the f one plan It has life
insurance coverage critical illness
benefit hospital income benefit
Accidental Deb benefit and projected
investment so for only 1,500 po You can
apply for the 5in one benefit plan and
also this is the for educational plan the
sun smarter life elite and health
insurance plan a very comprehensive
sunfit and well advantage that it covers
114 Major and minor critical illnesses
then This is also a sun Legacy Plan
Perfect for investment and retirement
plan you can pay one time or the single
L sum or pay Uh Twice or five times po
then This is another one Uh the Sun Life
assure which is 26 plus per day Uh it
doesn't have any cash value That's why
it's very
affordable So basically peas go po siya
ah is a five year renewable term plan so
you can get this one very Uh affordable
let's say it's very cheap ah
his price then the other one is the
sun peso maximizer ah it's an investment
Plan one time payment po ito Uh you can
choose from the denomination po ng peso
or Dollar po then for our Senior
citizens po they can also apply for Sun
senor care So basically this is all the
other information that you can
consider in applying for the stand
live insurance so that's all here po pong
This explanation and other
discussion po ng online appc so once
again My name is Denis ban I'm  your Sun
Life Financial advisor so feel free  to
ask questions or feel free to always
reach me out Uh through Viber through
WhatsApp through email or through
messenger po once again My name is
bulaon and God bless po